George Sugarman
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings, 1951-1992, undated, Series 5:; (Box 5; 0.2 linear feet)
  The series consists of materials written by Sugarman and by others. A journal, a lecture, notes, and miscellaneous writings by Sugarman are included. Essays written by others mainly concern Sugarman's exhibitions.
  The Writings series is organized into two subseries:
  5.1: Writings by George Sugarman, 1951-1992, undated
  5.2: Writings by Others, 1985-1987, undated
  - Writings by George Sugarman, 1951-1992, undated, 5.1:
    The subseries contains notes, a journal of thoughts Sugarman recorded while in Paris from 1951 to 1955, and a transcript of a slide presentation given by Sugarman. A large portion of the series consists of miscellaneous artist statements and drafts of essays concerning Sugarman's artistic theories about art in general and public sculpture in particular. Sugarman addresses topics such as the value of art, ways of seeing art, and ways of classifying art. Most of the miscellaneous writings are undated and untitled; many are just fragments. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by type of material and then chronologically.
    - Journal, 1951-1955 (Box 5)
    - Notes, 1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Slide Presentation, undated (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1978, undated, (6 folders) (Box 5)
  - Writings by Others, 1985-1987, undated, 5.2:
    Essays about Sugarman's drawing and sculpture exhibitions at Zabriskie Gallery, Dag Hammarskjold Plaza, and Kobe, Japan are included in the subseries. Also included is an essay about Zuka Mitelberg and a general survey of art. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by the author's last name.
    - Author Unknown, undated (Box 5)
    - Goldin, Amy, undated (Box 5)
    - Harper, Paula, undated (Box 5)
    - Higuchi, Shoichiro, undated (Box 5)
    - Storr, Robert, undated (Box 5)
    - Szeemann, Harald, undated, (in German) (Box 5)
    - Taylor, John Lloyd, undated (Box 5)
    - Webster, Sally, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
- Address and Appointment Books, 1972-1997, undated, Series 6:; (Boxes 5-6; 0.3 linear feet)
  The series consists of six address books and eight appointment books, which contain a few written notes and clippings. The original covers and bindings of the address and appointment books were removed for preservation reasons. The series is arranged by type of material and then chronologically.
  - Address Books, 1982-1990, undated, (6 folders) (Box 5)
  - Appointment Books, 1972-1997, (16 folders) (Box 6)
- Business and Financial Records, 1962-1998, undated, Series 7:; (Box 6; 0.4 linear feet)
  The series contains records for art-related expenses including invoices and statements of fabrication costs for Sugarman's sculptures by Lippincott, Inc., invoices for repair and maintenance work performed by Peter Capurso on Sugarman's sculptures, and receipts and invoices for art supplies and services. Personal expense records such as lease agreements for Sugarman's apartments, handwritten lists of miscellaneous living and business expenses, and income tax records from 1988 to 1990 are also included. Travel records, containing bills, receipts, and lists of expenses from Sugarman's many trips to Spain, Italy, France, and Germany from 1989-1990 are included as well. The series is arranged alphabetically by type of material and then chronologically. The travel records are subdivided by type of material and then arranged chronologically.
  - Income Tax Records, 1988-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Income Tax Returns, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Lease Agreements, 1962-1985 (Box 6)
  - Lippincott, Inc. Invoices and Statements, 1971-1990, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Lists of Expenses, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Maintenance Bills, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Peter Capurso Invoices, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Receipts for Art Supplies and Services, 1971-1998, undated, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Rent Bills, 1962-1990 (Box 6)
  - Travel Records, 1989-1990, undated, (6 folders) (Box 6)
- Printed Material, 1954-1999, undated, Series 8:; (Boxes 6-7, OV 8; 1.2 linear feet)
  The series contains business cards, clippings on a variety of topics, exhibition catalogs, and exhibition announcements for Sugarman and others. Brochures, maps, postcards, and eight guidebooks from Sugarman's trips to Japan, France, and other locations are also included in this series. The series is arranged alphabetically by type of material and then chronologically. The clippings are subdivided by subject and then arranged chronologically. The maps are subdivided by location. The guidebooks and handbooks are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Atlas, undated (Box 6)
  - Brochures, 1992-1995, undated, (5 folders; many in Japanese) (Box 6)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 6)
  - Clippings, 1970-1998, undated, (11 folders) (Box 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements for George Sugarman, 1954-1974, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements for Others, 1977-1999, (2 folders; see also OV 8) (Box 7)
  - Guidebooks and Handbooks, 1989-1995, undated, (8 folders) (Box 7)
  - Maps, undated, (7 folders) (Box 7)
  - Postcards, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1994, undated (Box 7)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements for Others, 1969-1997, (2 items) (Box OV 8)
- Photographs, 1966-1981, undated, Series 9:; (Box 7; 0.2 linear feet)
  The series contains mostly black-and-white photographs of George Sugarman working in the studio and at project sites, and of works of art by Sugarman. Several of the photographs were taken by Roxanne Everett for Lippincott, Inc. A few negatives are also included in the series. The series is organized by subject.
  - George Sugarman, 1969-1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - George Sugarman at Project Sites, 1969-1979, undated (Box 7)
  - George Sugarman in the Studio, 1969-1981, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Works of Art by George Sugarman, 1972-1979, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978, undated (Box 7)
  - Negatives, 1966, undated (Box 7)